Deirdre van der Zee

Web Designer & Developer

INFO



Address:

67 Ashthorn Avenue, Headford. Co.Galway, Ireland.



Phone:

087 6336896



Email:

deirdrevanderzee@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute / September 2018 -Present

Degree in Information Technology for Business (1.1)

Galway Mayo Institute of Technology / Galway / Ireland / 2001

Diploma in Computing, Business Computing (2.2)

Galway Mayo Institute of Technology / Galway / Ireland / 2000

Certificate in Computers with **Business Applications (2.2)**

Galway Mayo Institute of Technology / Galway / Ireland / 1999

PROFILE

With over fifteen years experience in website design and development for clients varying from food bloggers to charities, I feel confident that my abilities would prove an asset to any company. I am proficient in the use of HTML 5, CSS3 and WordPress and have strong experience in working with Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator and Experience Design. I have used these tools to successfully create websites and custom solutions for clients.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Designer/Developer Boon Agency Ltd / June, 2017 - June, 2018

- Responsibility for designing and developing both brochure and ecommerce websites using Wordpress and associated plugins
- Creating custom solutions to fit client requirements and providing training to clients when required
- Created graphics including icons and logos using Photoshop & Illustrator
- Design and manage client email campaigns
- Manage client email, domain, DNS and hosting requirements.

Senior Web Designer/Developer

MEDIALAB Ltd / March, 2013 - May, 2017

- Working directly with the client to establish project scope and time lines that takes the project from initial brief to final product
- Responsible for site development, deployment, SEO, security and maintenance
- Managed, maintained and updated existing web sites for customers and provided client training.
- Designed for and tested desktop and mobile sites, across multiple browsers
- Working with a wide range of clients including The Connacht Tribune, Galway Bay FM, Galway City Council, COPE Galway and NUI Galway Students Union.

Web Designer/Developer

An Rí Ltd / November, 2008 - October, 2009

Sole responsibility for the design and development of new websites and maintenance of existing websites.

Webmaster

Furntech Ltd / May, 2008 - October, 2008

- Member of a team charged with the redevelopment of Mattress.ie website
- Responsible for product creation and management for both Mattress.ie and Mattress.co.uk
- Created technical documentation, including user training guides, order flow charts and procedure guides, for a new content management system.

PROGRAMMING

- HTML/HTML 5
- CSS / CSS3
- SQL
- PHP
- JavaScript

S/W & DATABASES

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Experience Design
- Microsoft SQL Server,
- MySQL
- Microsoft Office Applications

CONTENT MGMT SYSTEMS

- Wordpress
- Joomla
- Magento
- Prestashop
- CMS Made Simple

INTERESTS





MUSIC

YOGA





BOOKS

SPORT





MOVIES

OUTDOORS

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Webmaster

Kennys Bookshop & Art Gallery Ltd / February, 2006 - April, 2008

- Redesigned both Kennys.ie and TheKennyGallery.ie which led to increase in traffic to both sites
- Oversaw changeover of stock cataloguing system, including redesign of reporting processes
- Managed the creation of catalogues and reports through Crystal Reports
- Implemented database manipulation and management
- Carried out Internal IT Support including Server Backup and maintenance.

Webmaster

Irish Emigrant Publications / September, 2001 - January, 2005

- Maintained and managed IrishEmigrant.com website
- Designed and created weekly and monthly HTML newsletters for electronic distribution
- Created dynamic features for site, including a voluntary donation system
- Redesigned site as part of team for major relaunch, resulting in substantial increase in site traffic
- Responsible for network maintenance and intra-office technical support.

Test Team Member

Nortel Networks (Ire) Ltd / June, 2000 - September, 2000

• Performed end-to-end testing of a major new software release for customer deployment while liaising with numerous departments to ensure the successful release of the software package.

KEY SKILLS

- Excellent problem solving and organisational skills
- Ability to work off own initiative and within a team
- A flexible approach to changing situations
- Demonstrated the ability to work diligently under pressure to meet deadlines
- Strong written and oral communication ability.

REFERENCES

Available on Request.